How well do you know your neighbor, your
co-workers, even your best friend? Well,
you might start secondguessing yourself
after watching Parasite: The Maxim, the
anime that takes its main character from
being an unsuspecting average Joe like
this.
>> Are you okay?
>> To a creature from your sci-fi thriller,
Nightmares.
Now that's a transformation. I've got a
good one for you today. So, let's get
right into it. The first episode opens
with an older couple standing in their
living room. There's nothing out of the
ordinary until the man's head splits
open to reveal rows of sharp teeth and
tentacles. Stranger Things just wrapped
recently. And this thing is giving the
demogorgan a run for its money. Even
worse, the poor woman just stands there
in horror while her husband bites off
her head. Now that's a cold open. I know
we all want to figure out what the hell
just went on there, but first we've got
to meet our main character, Shinichi.
The next scene opens with him asleep in
his bed while a disembodied voice tells
him that it was unfortunate that it
failed. The unfamiliar voice wakes
Shinichi and chalking it up to a bad
dream, he goes downstairs where his
parents, Kazayyuki and Nouko, are having
breakfast. They tease him about the
snake he saw in the night and how he
tied an earphone cord around his arm
while trying to catch it. First the
voice and now he had a night terror
about a snake. Man, this guy has some
weird dreams. Shinichi loses his
appetite after a spider crawls onto the
table. He's got a massive fear of bugs,
so he decides to head to school early.
On the way, one of his friends, a girl
named Marano, sneaks up on him from
behind. She tries to scare him, but he
reaches back and catches her hand
midair. When Shinichi turns around, he's
shocked to see Murano as if he didn't
just foil her plans. To make matters
worse, he grabs her chest, which earns
him a slap so strong that it knocks the
glasses from his face. I would say he
deserved it, but he genuinely seems
confused, as if he has no control over
his hand. Yeah, something is definitely
up with this guy. Another of Shinichi's
friends, a bookish girl named Yuko,
witnesses the entire thing and still
picks up his glasses for him. She asks
if there's something wrong with his
right hand, which he unconvincingly
denies. Later in class, Shinichi has a
flashback to the night before. Some sort
of alien creature tried to enter his
ear, but couldn't get past his earbuds.
It tried to go through his nose, but
Shinichi sneezed it out. When he saw the
thing, he mistook it for a snake and
tried to kill it with a book, only for
it to go into his hand. Yeah, something
tells me that this wasn't just a bad
dream.
>> What the hell is going on?
>> Shinichi's really having an off day at
school. Not only is his friend mad at
him, but he's in trouble with his
teachers for not paying attention. He
decides to call it a day and go home
early. But on his way, he encounters a
little girl chasing a ball across the
road. 5 seconds from getting hit,
Shinichi manages to save the girl and
stop the car in its tracks. Did does
this remind you guys of anything else?
No, just me. Okay. Anyway, after
Shinichi's freak show of superhuman
strength, he notices an eyeball staring
at him from his right hand, and he runs
home in terror. Back in his bedroom,
Shinichi tries stabbing his hand with a
knife. In retaliation, his right hand
transforms into an alien creature with
eyes and a mouth, but it doesn't know
how to speak beyond basic words. It
breaks the knife in half before tossing
it aside, preventing Shinichi from
hurting it. Then it goes back to sleep,
returning to the appearance of an
average human hand. Shinichi spends
hours searching for what the creature in
his hand could be, but comes up short.
Eventually, he just gives up and goes
downstairs to have dinner with his
parents. The next morning, Shinichi
wakes up to find the alien creature
protruding from his right hand while
studying biology books. The creature
explains that there is no mention of its
kind in human texts, and it doesn't know
where it came from. It does know that it
was supposed to enter and take over
Shinichi's brain, effectively killing
him and using his body as a vessel, but
it reached maturity while living in
Shinichi's hand, so it can no longer
take him over or live without him. The
creature suggests that they learn how to
coexist, so it doesn't die, and Shinichi
can keep his right arm. For some reason,
Shinichi agrees with this. Now that he's
sharing a body with a creature of
unknown origin, some things start to
change. When he goes down for breakfast,
he notably eats more than usual. He also
catches a spider and releases it
outside, overcoming his fears. More
importantly, he learns about a string of
vicious murders sweeping the nation. The
mention of murders seems to put
Shinichi's head on straight because he
decides to tell the police about his
alien hitchhiker. The organism talks him
out of it by bringing up how Shinichi
would become the government's newest
science project before it senses another
of its kind nearby, a parasite. Shinichi
finds the parasite possessing the mind
of a dog, which isn't the best host it
could have found. The parasite
transforms and tries to attack Shinichi,
but his parasite rips out the dog's
heart to kill it. The final scene of the
episode takes us back 2 days where a man
stabs a woman through the chest. He
laughs while looking toward the sky.
Around the same time, a parasite egg
lands on a satellite dish outside
Shinichi's window where it hatches. The
parasite's snake like form crawls
towards Shinichi. That's a lot to unpack
for a first episode, but it looks like
Shinichi has an alien invasion on his
hands. The second episode starts with a
parasite saving a woman from three men.
Of course, it's using a poor guy as a
vessel, so she has no idea that her
savior is a maneing alien. The parasite
offers to walk her home, only for the
three guys to catch up with them again.
Surrounded, the parasite decides to
eliminate witnesses by killing all four
of them just to be safe. Oh man. So much
for these being chivalous aliens.
Meanwhile, Shinichi is on his way to
school and he's made his peace with his
unique situation. He decides he needs to
call his parasite something and they
land on the name Migi. They also throw
the he him pronoun around, so that's
what I will be using. Later during gym
class, Shinichi is killing it in
basketball. I get the feeling he's not
the most athletic type on a typical day,
and Murano is swooning on the sidelines.
Another one of their classmates, a guy
called Nagayi, notices the sparks flying
between these two and stomps on
Shinichi's foot to throw him off his
game. Fortunately, Migi helps him get
another basket just to impress the girl.
After class, Shinichi apologizes for
inappropriately touching Murano, and she
says he can make it up to her by taking
her out for pancakes. We all agree that
she's counting that as a date, right? As
Murano leaves, Migi acts out again,
giving Shinichi a hard time for having a
crush. The teasing doesn't last long,
though, because that Nagai dude comes
back and tells Shinichi to follow him
outside. I saw this coming a mile away,
but Nagayi starts whailing on Shinichi,
saying that he's had a crush on Murano
since middle school. Dude, if that's the
case, why haven't you made a move yet?
You must know you don't stand a chance.
Anyway, Migi punches Nagayi in the face,
sending him running. Shinichi makes it
to the bathroom where he tells Migi not
to talk when other people are around.
Migi is more concerned about Shinichi's
human anatomy because alien. So Shinichi
has to book it out of the bathroom after
another student nearly walks in on a
very awkward conversation between our
dude and his right hand. Fortunately,
Shinichi manages to get home without
incident and even talks to Yuki about
the countrywide deaths, now being dubbed
the mincemeat murders. At home, Shinichi
tries to convince Migi to help him stop
the murders. When Migi disagrees because
it will needlessly endanger them both,
they have this very pleasant
interaction.
>> You're a demon,
>> Shinichi. I have done some research into
the concept of these demons you speak
of, and I would say that humans are the
life forms most closely resembling them.
>> Oh, yeah. That line's definitely going
to stick with me for a while. The next
day, Migi tells Shinichi that another
one of its kind is approaching. So,
Shinichi purposefully lures the parasite
to a park to confront it. However, when
the parasite catches up, it cuts off its
own arm to give Migi a new home. It
believes that they can share one host
and become stronger together. Even
though joining the other parasite would
mean killing Shinichi. Time stretches on
and Shinichi must be seeing his life
flash before his eyes before Migi kills
the other parasite. Of course, Migi
claims to have only done so because
there was no guarantee that transferring
to a new host would be successful. Oh,
but I know that you're just a big softy,
Migi. Sometime later, Shinichi takes
Murano out for those pancakes.
Afterward, they decide to go to the
park, but run into a group of guys
throwing rocks at a cat they buried in
the sandbox. Shinichi goes to rescue the
cat, but the teenagers throw rocks at
him. Of course, Shinichi catches the
rocks without looking and threatens to
eat them alive if they don't stop. The
teens get the hell out of Dodge. And if
Murano didn't have feelings for Shinichi
before, she definitely does now. Girl,
lock it in. Anyways, Shinichi and Murano
walk home holding hands and Murano asks
if he's really Shinichi. Uh, he says yes
and technically it's not a lie. The
episode closes with a scene of the
parasite from the opening scene standing
in a room with an unnamed woman. They're
nude. They're definitely both aliens.
And I've got a feeling we might have
some baby parasites in the near future.
Yeah. In the third episode, things are
ramping up and fast. The mince meat
murders have progressed to include 84
victims and counting, which means
there's at least as many bloodthirsty
parasites running around. While
attending school one day, Migi senses a
fellow parasite in the body of
Shinichi's new math teacher, Ryoko. Of
course, they can't spot one without
getting noticed themselves. So, Shinichi
and Riyoko find themselves in a bit of a
stalemate. Riyoko wants to blend in with
human society. So, she's not planning a
murder spree like the rest of their
species. She and Migi agree to meet
somewhere more private after school to
discuss the parasites future. At the
meeting spot, Riyoko catches Shinichi
and Migi offg guard by bringing along a
friend. Another parasite that goes by
the name A. A is the parasite from the
last episode who hooked up with that
unknown woman. Yeah, that woman is Rio.
From the start, A doesn't like or trust
Shinichi. However, they're all caught
off guard by Riyoko revealing that she's
pregnant with a human baby.
>> And the result might surprise you. I am
now pregnant, Mr. Izumi.
>> Apparently, regardless of being with
another parasite or a human, a
parasite's child will always be a normal
human. Huh. Okay. That is not a twist
that I saw coming. The informational
meeting bores a so he ends up leaving
early, slipping away from the more
level-headed aliens. The next day, he
shows himself again. Only this time,
it's to terrorize Shinichi's school. He
goes on a rampage, forcing students and
staff to evacuate the building. To
protect himself, Shinichi goes to an
unoccupied part of the school where he
builds a barricade out of tables while
Migi tells him to make use of his still
working brain by using it as a weapon.
They barely arm themselves before A
breaks past their barricade, prepared
for a fight. The fourth episode opens
where we last left off with Shinichi
facing off against A. In those brief
seconds between life and death, Shinichi
grapples with the fear overtaking his
senses. Apparently, he and Migi had made
a plan for situations like this, which
requires Migi to play defense to protect
them and Shinichi to play offense and
kill the parasite. Shinichi calms his
nerves enough to get in close and stab A
through the chest with a chair leg. It's
gnarly. Blood spills from the leg like
it's a running faucet. You can't see me
grimacing behind the screen, but take my
word for it. That's a brutal way to go.
A should die from the sheer amount of
blood loss he sustains, but he escapes,
hoping to merge with Ryoko and share her
body. Instead, Ryoko traps him in a room
and blows him up by igniting a gas leak.
After the event, Shinichi gets some time
off from school, but classes ultimately
resume. On the first day back, the staff
have a meeting to discuss the
implications of Riyoko's pregnancy and
the fact that she can't tell them who
the baby's father is. They're judging
her pretty hard. So, to avoid further
suspicion, Riyoko resigns from her
teaching position. Listen, even if she
wasn't a brain leachching parasite, I
would still support quitting after that
meeting. Anywh who, Shinichi stops
Riyoko right before she leaves campus,
but refrains from killing her because of
her human child. She then tells him that
she plans to run experiments on her
child when they're born and will eat
them when they're no longer useful. Huh,
you've gotten yourself into quite the
pickle there, haven't you, Shinichi?
Riyoko goes on to say that all species
have basic instincts, a set of rules
programmed into them from birth, and
that hers require her to devour
humankind. She then goes to kill
Shinichi, but sensing a change in him,
she lets him live. Later that night, the
real Riyoko's mother comes to visit her.
She's worried because the school called
to tell her that Riyoko resigned earlier
in the day. A mother knows things and
she's not there 5 minutes before she
realizes the thing standing in front of
her isn't her daughter.
>> It's not right. Something's very wrong.
Who are you? Byoko, where's my Rio?
>> The picture perfect replication isn't
enough. The parasites can't fake the
life in a human's eyes. Alien Riyoko
kills her mom before she can call for
help. Meanwhile, Shinichi's parents tell
him about a countryside vacation over
dinner. Obviously, Shinichi is against
them going on a trip while there are
murderous aliens on the loose. Migi
reminds him that the parasites prefer
higher traffic areas, so they should be
safe in the country. The next morning,
Shinichi apologizes for his outburst and
encourages them to go on their trip.
That's when his mom calls him out for
being different and begs him to tell her
why he's changed so much. He chalks it
up to not wanting to be lonely and
promises that he's fine. She isn't
convinced, but agrees to go on the
vacation. On the next day, they leave.
She's the last one out the door,
promising Shinichi that they'll be back
soon. Aw, those are definitely her
famous last words, aren't they? The
fifth episode begins with a couple
driving. And the woman is definitely
weird, like wrapping the seat belt
around her head because she doesn't know
how it works. Weird. Obviously, that
distracts the driver and he crashes the
car. The woman dies on impact, so the
parasite attempts to transfer itself to
the man. Unfortunately for it, moving
between bodies isn't easy. On his way to
school the following day, Migi points
out that people are starting to notice
changes in Shinichi. These changes even
make sense because fusing with an alien
should change him on a physical and
psychological level. Shinichi hates this
theory, especially because Ryoko sensed
a change in him so significant that she
let him live. As Shinichi is having an
identity crisis, he comes across his
bully Nagai, who is getting beaten up by
a guy named Mitsuo and his gang.
Shinichi thinks it's inhuman nature to
be self-sacrificial.
So, to prove a point, he goes in to
rescue Nagai. The problem is Migi is
asleep at this point. So, he's
defenseless as the gang members beat him
to a pulp, too. Fortunately, the female
student who hangs with the gang, Kana,
calls Mitsuo off because she doesn't
think it's a fair fight. Oddly enough,
when she goes to check on Shinichi, she
looks into his eyes and knows there's
something wrong with him. Even though
Kana calls the fight there, Mitzo comes
back for more the next day. except this
time he and his gang attack Murano,
scaring her and infuriating Shinichi.
Obviously, he's going to fight to save
his friend, but he gets busted up pretty
good this time, too. The difference is
that Migi is awake for this fight, and
Shinichi needs to keep his parasite from
murdering the gang members. Fortunately,
Nagai shows up in the nick of time with
a group of other students who are there
to rescue him. The gang members know
they're outnumbered, so they call it a
day. Safe again, Murano and Shinichi
walk home together, and Shinichi even
invites her to stay over since his
parents are out of town, but she
declines. Meanwhile, the parasite from
the episode's opening drags itself
across the highway. It can barely keep
itself together in this male form and
desperately searches for a female host.
That's how it ends up on the same beach
as Shinichi's parents, where his dad,
Kazuyuki, watches it behead his mom,
Nouko, in cold blood. Later, Kazuyuki
survives the wounds given to him by the
parasite and drags himself to the
nearest phone booth to call Shinichi.
He's barely coherent, but all he needs
to say is the word monster for Shinichi
to know what happened. God damn, poor
kid. The next morning, Nouko comes home
and even though Migi tells him that the
parasite is no longer his mom, he
prevents Migi from attacking her.
Meanwhile, Nouko's parasite talks about
going back to finish off Kazuyuki before
stabbing Shinichi through the heart. The
sixth episode opens with the brutal
scene of Shinichi bleeding out in his
home's hallway. With precious seconds to
spare, Migi decides to risk it all by
forming itself to act as Shinichi's
heart while simultaneously working to
repair the damaged one. It is a lengthy
process that takes a full day to
complete with Shinichi unconscious the
entire time. When he finally wakes, he
realizes that he doesn't need glasses to
see and that he has a wicked scar,
perfect for any anime protagonist. While
he was out cold, Migi kept him hydrated
with some nice sugar water. So,
Shinichi's not feeling the best when he
gets a call from Sakura Hospital.
Surprisingly, Kazuyuki managed to
survive his injuries and is in stable
condition. So, Shinichi catches the
first fairy to the island that his
parents were visiting, all while
plotting to kill the parasite that took
over Nouko. We are in his revenge arc,
ladies and gentlemen. Meanwhile,
Kazuyuki tries telling the authorities
that his wife was murdered, but they and
the hospital staff convince him that the
parasite attack was a nightmare he's
confusing for reality. In defense of the
police, Parasite Nouko went back to
their hotel, interacted with the staff,
and checked out. So, it seems to them
like she ran out on her family. Shinichi
decides that it's time to tell his dad
everything about parasites. But when he
gets to the hospital, Kazuyuki insists
Nouko's death was a dream, even though
he knows it's not true. Shinichi lets it
go and tells his dad that he'll stay
near the hotel while he recovers. Of
course, he's also sticking around to
keep an eye out for that parasite,
believing it will come back to kill
Kazuyuki soon enough. On his way to the
island, Shinichi met a girl named Makiko
on the ferry, and he stays at her
family's inn. Before going to bed that
night, Migi drops a bombshell on
Shinichi. Since he has used so much
energy to repair Shinichi's heart, he
has to sleep for 4 hours every day. And
during that time, he's unresponsive to
the outside world. That means he can't
sense other parasites or fight them off.
The next day, Shinichi is sitting
outside the hospital when Makiko comes
to sit with him. She bluntly asks if he
has a girlfriend, but then he bolts
upright because Migi senses another
parasite down by the beach. Shinichi
takes off at the speed of light. Not
really, but he's real freaking fast. And
then he leaps over the seaw wall to
reach the shore. You know, he's really
reminding me of someone. I just can't
put my finger on it. The episode ends
with Shinichi confronting the parasite
on the beach, but it's not who he
expects. In the seventh episode, we meet
a brand new character, an absolute
sweetheart of a man named Mamoru Uda. It
turns out that he's in the same boat as
Shinichi, only that his parasite lives
rentree in his mouth. On the day the
parasites landed in Japan, Mamoru
planned to take his own life by jumping
into the sea. His parasite, sensing that
Mamoru would soon drown, prioritized
helping him breathe instead of infecting
his brain. Thus, their weird
cohabitation was born. In the present,
Shinichi and Mamoru go to the hospital
roof to talk in private where Shinichi
shares his story. Mamoru cries for him
and his mom before promising to help him
locate parasite Nouko if he can. Later
that night, Migi enlightens Shinichi
with even more delightful information.
Just like Migi was changed from entering
Shinichi's heart, so was he. About 30%
of Migi entered Shinichi's bloodstream,
which is now altering him in unforeseen
ways. That's why he can run fast, jump
high distances, and even pass an eye
exam with flying colors. Shinichi
wonders if those changes include his
brain, too. I mean, he's got to ask. The
man's got to be prepared if he starts
feeling a desire to eat other people.
Also, he realizes that he hasn't cried
about losing his mom, which makes him
feel like he's losing touch with his
human side. The next day, Mamodu calls
Shinichi because he senses Nouko in town
and tracks her down. Of course, Shinichi
tells him to run before he's offed on
the spot, and our guys start running
toward each other, hoping to meet in the
middle. Unfortunately, Shinichi isn't
quick enough, and Mumoru finds himself
on a cliff edge, cornered by Nouko. They
don't stand a chance, but his parasite
realizes Nouko's fighting in a specific
pattern before she manages to stab them
in the heart, sending them tumbling over
the cliff to the beach below. On his way
to Mamoru, Shinichi's fate takes an
unfortunate turn when Migi falls asleep.
As he does, he turns Shinichi's right
arm into a blade, giving him a way to
defend himself. Even though Migi advised
him to leave and save himself, Shinichi
still goes to confront Nouko. To his
surprise, he can anticipate her every
move.
>> I can see it. I can see every move it
makes. There it is.
>> Like, come on. He's a badass now, too.
Shinichi manages to hold his own in the
fight and even gains the upper hand. But
just as he's about to deliver the
killing blow, he's overwhelmed with
flashbacks of his mom. He can't bring
himself to do it after all. But luckily,
Mamorusu sneaks up from behind, taking
her out for both of them. His parasite
had moved his vital organs out of the
way just before letting him get hit,
creating the illusion of a killing blow
so they could get in a sneak attack.
Ooh, hell yeah. We've got brains and
brawn over here. A double threat.
Anyway, the next day, Kazuyuki is
discharged from the hospital, so
Shinichi says goodbye to Mako, not
planning to see her again. Before they
leave, he and his dad stop to watch the
ocean. Kazuyuki tells him that his mom
always loved him and that she didn't
suffer in her final moments. Hearing
that and having avenged Nouko, Shinichi
collapses. Don't worry though, he's just
sleeping and it's probably the best nap
of his life. Sometime later, he returns
to school, but the Shinichi everyone
knew and loved is now an entirely new
person. In the eighth episode, we start
in a dark room with Riyoko. She's with
another parasite that's feasting on a
corpse. She tells the parasite to track
down Shinichi and keep a close eye on
him because he'll be invaluable in the
research for the future of their kind. I
don't like the sound of that. But the
parasite puts on the face of a high
schooler planning to infiltrate
Shinichi's social circle. At the same
time, Kana is loitering outside the
school to catch up with Shinichi because
his weird vibe has enchanted her. Mitzo,
the gang leader, shows up to talk with
her, but gets mad when she brushes him
off in favor of Shinichi. Obviously,
he's jealous, so he goes to the school
and lures Shinichi into a nearby alley
for a conversation. Shinichi tries to
warn him, but Mitsuo picks up a fight.
>> It was at this moment that he knew
heeded up
>> while serving looks too. Is there
anything this guy can't do? Murano shows
up to catch the tail end of the fight
and the two of them walk home together.
She again brings up how different he
seems, especially since coming back from
his trip. Shinichi tries to play it off,
but there's no denying it. He is
different. Don't just take my word for
it either. The following morning, while
they're walking to school, Shinichi
saves a puppy getting hit by a car. Its
injuries are too severe to heal, so
Shinichi and Murano sit with it until it
dies. Then he throws it into a trash
can. I don't know about you, but that
gives me some serious ick. They're
literally at the park. He could have
buried the puppy. Murano also thinks
he's acting uncharacteristically cold
and leaves. Shinichi can't figure out
what he did wrong, which is a glaring
red flag if you ask me. He has to ask
Migi for help understanding the
situation. Migi, he goes back and buries
the puppy later, so he may not be
completely hopeless. Anyway, Shinichi
goes to school only for Murano to avoid
him. While he's there, he picks up on a
nonviolent parasite in the area and goes
to meet with him in a secluded
stairwell. That's where he meets the new
parasite from the beginning of the
episode, who introduces himself as
Shimada. He's kind of a jerk, instantly
showing off and breaking school records
during their gym class. He tells
Shinichi that he has no intention of
causing a stir at the school, that he
follows a similar diet to that of
humans, and that he wants to find a way
for parasites and humans to coexist. He
also reveals that Ryoko's going by a new
name, Reiko. Obviously, Shinichi doesn't
trust this guy, but he isn't going to
start a fight. After school, Kana bumps
into Shimada, thinking that he is
Shinichi. She incorrectly assumes that
she is sensing Shinichi because he's her
soulmate. Someone's a romantic, not
because he's part alien. Shimada tries
to drag Kana away so they can talk, but
Shinichi arrives just in time to save
her. He then walks Kana to the train
station and after hearing about her
unique sixth sense, warns her not to use
it as it'll lead her to bad people. In
the final moments of the episode, we get
to see Yuki again, who stays up late
making a lifelike portrait of Shimada.
Girl, you've got questionable taste in
men. Speaking of Shimada, we also see
him change his face, approach a lost
woman, and lure her into a secluded area
where he proceeds to eat her. So, we
can't trust anything that comes out of
this guy's mouth. Got it. The ninth
episode starts like an average day,
except Kana bumps into Shimada again. He
has his eye on her because of her sixth
sense, but can't hurt her because
they're in public and are interrupted by
Mitsuo. Obviously, he gets jealous of
Kana talking to another guy, so he tries
to start a fight. Shimada roughs him up
a bit, but lets him go before heading to
school. Yuko witnesses this from afar
because she's stalking her new crush.
After school, Shinichi comes home to
find his dad entertaining some guests.
It's a nice change of pace because
Kazuyuki has picked up a nasty drinking
habit and spends most nights down in a
bottle. Now he has three men in black
types confirming the existence of
parasites, confirming his wife's death,
and swearing Kazuyuki to secrecy to
avoid creating a mass panic. They even
have a profile artist there who drew an
accurate depiction of a parasite. After
the police leave, Kazuyuki tells
Shinichi what really happened to his
mom. Shinichi pretends to be surprised
and keeps Migi's existence a secret.
Elsewhere, Reicho is having a meeting
with another parasite. They discuss
their kind's purpose and why they came
to Earth in the first place. They
determine that humans are a poison to
their own planet. So, the parasites need
to eat them to restore Earth's natural
balance. Also happening across town,
Yuko finds the drawing of the parasite
in her older brother's sketchbook since
he's the sketch artist who visited
Kazuyuki. He plays it off saying it's
just a monster that he drew.
Unfortunately, Yuko's destined to learn
the truth when she watches a runaway
baseball crack Shimatada in the head. It
takes out a chunk of his skull, which he
miraculously heals before members of the
school's baseball team come to check on
him. As Shimada goes to leave the
school, Mitsuo stops him. This guy
doesn't know when to quit as he takes
Shimato into an abandoned yard for a
fullon fight. It goes without planning
that Shimada plans to kill the entire
group, but Shinichi manages to intervene
at the last second. Not only does he
call Shimada off, but he also convinces
Mitzuo and his friends to stop causing
trouble. Shinichi having to clean up
after Shimada makes him a little more
irritated than usual, which puts Morano
off. When she finally starts talking to
him again after the puppy incident, she
brings up how much he's changed and asks
once more if he's really Shinichi. his
response. He yells at her and tells her
to shut up. Dude,
she nichi, I know you're going through
something, but I don't think you deserve
the girl. He feels guilty about it
afterwards, but Migi reassures him that
he's only becoming more resilient.
Sure. Uh, that's one way to look at it.
Meanwhile, Yuko follows Shimada as he
leaves school. She tails him as he goes
into the city and eventually watches as
he changes his face. That's not
something you see every day. So, she
goes home to confront her brother about
the monster in his sketchbook. Her
brother comes clean about the parasites
and tells her to be careful moving
forward. Yuko, who I can only assume is
blinded by love at this point, decides
to confront Shimada at school the next
day. She does just that, going through
her paint supplies to find anything she
could use as a lethal weapon. She
settles on some chemicals and keeps the
bottle close as Shimada enters the empty
classroom. When she asks if he really
eats other humans, Shimada has no choice
but to reveal his true form.
>> Do you really do all those horrible
things to people, Shimata?
>> Not good.
Not at all. Yuko is going to be his next
meal. Fortunately though, Migi senses
Shimatada's murderous intent and warns
Shinichi. The episode ends with him
bolting up in class, demanding to know
where his friend is before it's too
late. In the 10th episode, Yuko fights
for her life. She throws the chemical
bottle at Shimada, and when the liquid
hits his bare skin, it burns. Whatever
she dowsed him with, it hurts and it
gives her a few precious seconds to
sneak onto the window's ledge. Students
in the schoolyard watch as she scales a
ledge and then jumps into a nearby tree.
She falls to the ground, but makes it
out alive. Some kids see Shimatada
through the window and go to
investigate. Those chemicals really did
a number on Shimada. He goes on a
murderous rampage throughout the school,
unable to reshape his face into his
human disguise. He kills the two
students who went to investigate and
then several more afterwards. As news of
an armed attacker spreads, the school
evacuates. When Shinichi realizes Morano
and her classmates haven't made it
outside, he goes back in to rescue her.
It requires seeing a fullon massacre and
he nearly loses his nerve.
>> Shinn, calm down.
>> Fortunately, he gets back up in time to
find Murano before Shimada does. After
carrying Murano to safety and jumping
out a window to get outside, he learns
that Shimada's heading toward the school
roof. Migi tries to get Shinichi to
leave it to the police, but they're
getting sliced and diced left and right.
So instead, Shinichi takes a rock to a
nearby roof. Aided by Migi's brute
strength, he launches the rock at such a
high velocity that it smashes through
Shimata's chest on the school roof,
crushing his heart. Uh, top 10 anime
deaths. I never would have seen that
coming. What a curveball.
get it cuz he threw it like a baseball.
Sometime later, members of the
government hold a secret meeting to
discuss the increased sighting of
parasites. While they don't want to
cause a mass panic, they have developed
a way to distinguish parasites from
humans. If a small enough piece of a
parasite's DNA separates from the main
body, it'll shrivel up and die. They
pull some strings and start a trend of
people saying hello by pulling out
strands of someone else's hair. Weird
that it caught on, but hey, if it'll
keep people safe, people move on quickly
around here because it's not long before
Shinichi and his friends return to
school after the Shimada massacre. In
the 11th episode, a woman pulls her
friend's hair out after a night of
drinking. She's wasted, but even she
can't miss how the man's hair wiggles in
her hand like a worm, separated from the
rest of its body. When it disintegrates
in her hand, she knows he's actually a
parasite. Yeah. So, despite not wanting
to cause mass panic, it seems like the
word is finally getting around about the
alien invaders. The man ends up killing
her and dragging her body into the
woods. Meanwhile, Kana's having some
fever dreams about Shinichi.
Ones where he comes to save her from
monsters and they share a passionate
kiss afterward. She's down bad and keeps
following him around even after he told
her to stay away. She even takes a
chance by talking to Morano, getting a
feel for the situation to see if she
would have an opportunity with Shinichi.
For the record, she does think she still
stands a chance, and she's trying to
steal Murano's man. That aside, the
parasites are causing some trouble on
the other side of town. A new parasite
named Gooto wants to see how he would
hold up against an armed group. So he
raids and attacks a Yakuza warehouse,
taking out everyone inside. It's another
bloodbath. And despite there being
civilian witnesses, he gets in and out
without being caught. Back with
Shinichi, he and Murano go out on a real
date together. Finally, they have fun,
but Murano can't shake the feeling that
he's not the same person she met during
their first year as high schoolers.
Despite that, they still share a kiss
before calling it a night. Something
that Kana witnesses because she's been
following them around. That's not weird
at all. That night, Kana calls Shinichi
asking to meet up for one last favor.
The next day, Shinichi beats Kana to
their meeting place. Imagine his
surprise when he discovers a large group
of parasites petitioning the public to
vote for them. The lead candidate, Teshi
Hiokawa, is running for mayor.
Unfortunately, if Migi can sense the
parasite political party, it means that
they can feel him, too. And it doesn't
take long for Goto to pick him out of
the crowd. In the 12th episode, Shinichi
and Migi grapple with the fact that
parasites are now taking powerful
positions. Migi explains it well as
having Hiroka as the mayor will ensure
the parasites have a leader who can
brush their murders under the rug,
provide them with low-risk humans to
hunt, and safe locations to feed in. It
makes sense. And to their horror,
Hirokawa does win the election. So after
meeting up with Kana at the rally in the
previous episode, she mentioned again
that she could feel his presence and
that of others. Kana also starts
transmitting her own faint signal,
making her detectable for parasites.
Shinichi wants to tell her everything,
but Migi forbids it. So naturally,
Shinichi waits until Migi takes one of
his naps to meet up with Kana in
private. In an abandoned building, he
lays out everything from beginning to
end. She doesn't believe him and thinks
that he's created an elaborate story to
make her stop bothering him, but he
insists it's the truth and promises to
show her Migi. When Migi agrees to meet
Kana, Shinichi has to cancel a date with
Murano for another secret meeting with
Kana. Unfortunately, Kana wants to prove
herself to Shinichi by tracking him down
with her sixth sense. She leaves her
phone at home as she wanders into the
city, hoping to hone in on him. Instead,
she follows her power to a murderous
parasite who doesn't hesitate to kill
her on the spot. Migi also sensed the
same parasite. So, Shinichi wasn't far
behind. He witnesses Kana being stabbed
through the heart, and in a moment of
adrenaline and rage, he rips out the
parasite's heart with his bare hand.
While he wasn't fast enough to save
Kana, he does hold her in his arms as
she dies. At least in the end, she got
to be with the person she loved. I wish
we could have learned more about her
powers, though, like why she had them
and how they even worked. Later, during
her funeral, police investigator
Hiramama discusses Shinichi's
circumstances with a colleague. First
his mom, now Kana. They also took a
strand of Shinichi's hair, but unlike
other parasites, his doesn't react. On
his way home from the funeral, Shinichi
is also stopped by Mitsuo, the gang
member, and Kana's ex-boyfriend. He
jumps Shinichi for her death and for not
seeming to mourn her, but gets clocked
in the nose for his trouble. But he does
bother Shinichi, who can't bring himself
to shed a tear over a lost friend. He
even goes into the woods to bash his
head against a tree. All blood, no
tears.
At least my blood's still red.
>> He's definitely a glass half full kind
of guy. In the 13th episode, Shinichi
tries to recover after Kana's death.
Unfortunately, news has started to
spread around his school about the
murder in the next town over, the
victim, and who found the body. Everyone
knows that Kana and Shinichi were
friends, and some find it suspicious
that he's acting normal after such a
traumatic event. I can't lie, it's kind
of concerning. And Shinichi thinks so,
too. He's started to have panic attacks
or intense moments of pain in his heart
where he struggles to breathe. They come
and go within an instant, as if his
human and alien sides are at war with
each other. The parasites are also on
the move with Hirokawa designating
specific feeding locations for his
followers to ensure a longer survival.
Shinichi doesn't notice it at first, but
a private investigator has started
following him and documenting every
aspect of his life. The investigator,
Kuramorei, was hired by Reiko to help
her keep tabs on her favorite research
subject. When Kuramorei comes up short,
Reiko hires a few guys to rough Shinichi
up. Shinichi wins that fight without
breaking a sweat, and Kuramorei gets it
on camera. There's no sign of Migi, but
it's not every day a high schooler takes
on four grown men and wins. Sometime
later, Shinichi returns to the site of
Kana's death to try to tap into his
human emotions. He wants to relive the
experience so he can actually mourn her.
Instead, Migi spots Kuramorei taking
photos of them and attacks without
mercy. Migi wants to kill Kuramorei on
the spot, but Shinichi manages to hold
him back, allowing the detective to
escape with his life. At the very least,
they do manage to get his camera and
delete the footage, but Shinichi starts
to worry about the government coming to
get him at any moment. By the end of the
episode, Shinichi's working up the nerve
to finally tell Murano everything he
would need to explain if the police came
to arrest him. Unfortunately, Migi gets
in the way, threatening to kill Murano
if she knew the truth. Murano knows that
Shinichi is keeping secrets from her, so
she leaves him in the lurch. In the 14th
episode, Reiko ends her working
relationship with Kuramorei. For
whatever reason, she doesn't kill him on
the spot, and he can't let what he
experienced go. Against her advice, he
continues a private investigation on
Shinichi. If nothing else, he just needs
to prove to himself that he's not crazy.
Shinichi is also worried about his
secret getting out, so he calls in
backup to help him track down the
investigator. That's right, guys. Mamoru
and his mouthy parasite are back for a
team up. Kuramorei is not hard to find
because he's actively stalking Shinichi.
So, they get him in a car and take him
to a secluded area for a little chat. To
Kuramot's credit, he actually hears our
guys out before deciding to let his
investigation go. Since she lost her
investigator, Reiko reaches out to
Shinichi to set up a meeting. She
attends a university lecture about
humanity, our altruism, and how it may
actually be our selfish drive to survive
that pushes us to do good things for the
world. That's a hot take, but Reiko's
totally focused on it, especially when
her professor brings up the way mothers
care for their children to ensure they
pass on their DNA. Speaking of children,
she gave birth to her son a few episodes
back, but he's just been chilling. She
hasn't started her experiments on him
because he's too little, but she does
take him to the lecture with her and to
her meeting with Shinichi. During their
conversation, she realizes that a
parasite must have killed Shinichi's
mother. That triggers Shinichi and he
considers killing Reiko, but she uses
her baby as a shield. He tries to chase
her down when she leaves the university,
but loses her. He runs for a while,
eventually running into a streetside
fortune teller. She reads his palm,
telling him that to fill the hole in his
heart, he has to confront the person who
caused it so he can have closure. He
smiles at her all creepy like and tells
her that he already killed her. Uh,
Shinichi, maybe you shouldn't go around
confessing to murder. In the 15th
episode, another parasite lures an
innocent woman to her death. He takes
her to one of their chosen feeding
areas. All the while being followed by
another private investigator. Only this
time, they're a friend of Kuramorei, who
agreed to help him continue his private
investigation. It just so happens that
he's changed his targets to Reiko and
her associates. Of course, the parasite
knows he's being watched and just kills
the PI. Knowing the last place his
friend went, Kuramorei reaches out to
Shinichi for help and takes him to the
feeding area. When they get there, they
find another parasite about to feed.
While he can't save the poor woman, he
does kill the parasite. Kuramorei knew
nothing about the parasites, but it's
one thing to hear about crazy monsters
and another to see them at work. He
actually does lay off after that and
lets Migi destroy the last of his
research. Meanwhile, the parasites meet
with their mayor, Hiokawa, about the
absolute pain in the ass Shinichi has
become. They decide to kill him as soon
as possible, but Reiko tells them to
bring his body back in one piece so she
can dissect him. Hiwa wants to send out
Goto, the parasite that killed the
Yakuza a while back, but Goto suggests
sending a parasite named Miki instead.
The next day, Migi senses a trio of
parasites moving towards Shinichi with
murderous intent. Shinichi leaves town
to find a more remote setting for
combat. But on the way, Migi falls
asleep. Man, he has terrible timing.
Without his parasite, his super sense,
or a way to defend himself, Shinichi
just runs around for hours. Eventually,
Miki does catch up with him. And look,
y'all can tell me if I'm wrong, but he
looks pretty chill. He follows Shinichi
around with the pair eventually hitching
rides on the back of some trucks to
chase one another through the
countryside. When Migi finally wakes up,
he reveals that the reason Shinichi
never ran into the other two parasites
is that all three of them were occupying
Miki's body. What the what? In the 16th
episode, Mayor Hirokawa and his
associates decide to get rid of
Kuramorei by blowing up his office.
Miraculously, he survives, but their
stunt kills his wife and daughter. At
the same time, Shinichi and Migi square
off against Miki, who isn't very
coordinated. They manage to cut off his
head just for Gooto to take his place.
Goto is one of the three parasites
sharing a body with Miki. So, he just
takes over as the primary host. The
problem with that is that he actually
knows what he's doing and can tear
Shinichi to shreds. Our guys don't stand
a chance, so Migi forces their truck to
sideswipe enough to knock Gooto to the
road, giving them a chance to escape. He
lowkey sacrificed the two humans in the
other truck, but what's a guy to do?
Later, Shinichi learns about Kuramorei
and his family. He's had some run-ins
with the police in the past due to his
connections to various parasite cases.
To keep Kuramorei out of trouble, he
suggests that Kuramorei reach out to the
lead investigator on the parasite case,
Hiama, for help. Kuramorei does just
that, going to the police for
questioning. Unfortunately, he later
leaves the station to hunt down Reiko,
hoping to avenge his family himself, cuz
that's always a good idea. Once Shinichi
realizes the parasites are still coming
after Kuramorei and that they didn't
hesitate to kill his loved ones, he
calls his dad and begs him to get out of
town. Luckily, his dad doesn't put up a
fight and clears the heck out of there.
Shinichi stays home, though, which seems
counterproductive. But I guess the
parasites know where to find him, so
what's the point in even running? The
stress must be getting to him though
because he's having some weird dreams
where he talks to Migi in his sleep. Not
that he remembers their conversations
come morning, which Migi totally hates.
Anyways, there's trouble in Paradise
with the parasites. Reiko has acted as
their head researcher since day one, but
she's starting to question their purpose
on Earth, her role as a mother, and how
far humans will go to protect their own.
Her new views and public outbursts make
the other members of Hiokawa's parasites
view her as a threat. Obviously, they
try to kill her. The 17th episode starts
where we left off as a group of
parasites ambushes Reiko. She's one of
the first baddies that we've met, and
she's a smart one, too. So, it doesn't
take her long to win the fight and
return home. When she gets there,
though, she finds her baby is missing.
There's a little ransom note left behind
by Kuramorei, who stole her son and
demands she meet him if she wants to see
her child again. As Reiko studies human
nature, her heart has also grown three
sizes. And by that, I mean she actually
seems to care for this kid. So, she goes
to the meeting. Later, Hiramama and some
other investigators break into her
apartment, also finding Kuramorei's
note. Reiko has time to kill before her
meeting. So she goes to Shinichi's house
to look around. There she finds some
pictures of his mom and once again faces
her greatest enemy yet, motherhood. I
don't think she could ignore these
maternal instincts even if she tried.
And she does try though, talking with
Shinichi from his home phone to ask him
to attend her meeting with Kuramorei. As
she's leaving his house, she bumps into
Murano, who later follows her all the
way to the park, where she plans to have
her meeting. Fortunately, Murano loses
Reiko, keeping her away from all the
action. At her meeting with Kuramorei,
she listens as he calls her heartless,
cruel, emotionless, and so on. He
pretends like he's going to throw her
baby over the side of the building,
believing she won't care if her son
lives or dies, but he's dead wrong.
Reiko stabs him through the abdomen in
an instant, saving her baby and sending
Kuramorei toppling over the rail. When
the police make it to the meeting spot,
they find Kuramorei on the brink of
death, using his last words to give them
Reiko's description. The police fan out
to search for her. While all of this is
going down, Shinichi also arrived at the
park and started using Migi to track
down Reiko. The episode ends with the
two of them coming face to face. The
18th episode starts with an exciting
revelation. As the only science and
research-driven parasite in this series,
aside from Migi, Reiko has made some
fascinating discoveries about her own
species. As she and Shinichi have their
staredown in the park, she decides to
share some of her findings, like the
fact that her kind can live off of the
same diet as humans, meaning they're
capable of coexisting peacefully with
each other. The problem is that most
parasites give in to their desire to
devour humans, making them the apex
predator. As they talk about their
species, the police show up and surround
the area, preventing Reiko's escape by
laying into her with gunfire. She
doesn't fight back, but instead shields
her baby as she carries him to Shinichi.
Her dying wish is that her son be raised
right in a loving home like a proper
human. In those moments, Shinichi sees
his mom in Reiko and finally mourns her
alongside everyone else he's lost. As
he's breaking down, Murano appears on
the scene, having followed the sound of
gunshots to find him. Unfortunately, our
two love birds don't get to catch up. As
the police take Shinichi to a research
facility. While they don't think he's a
parasite, they do think it's strange
that he keeps getting involved with
them. They suspect he might have psychic
abilities like Kana. And to test that
theory, they bring in someone who does
have parasite sensing powers. Who's this
new character with Kana's sixth sense?
You're likely asking me on the other
side of the screen. Well, dear viewers,
it's none other than a serial killer on
death row. Yeah, he's a total freak, and
his name is Uragami. He's gross. He's
got bad vibes, and he's just as
bloodthirsty as the parasites they're
hunting. More importantly, he does sense
something strange about Shinichi. In the
19th episode, Uragami locks in.
He starts reminiscing about his past and
we get a nice flashback to his time as a
serial killer. This guy did it all.
Whatever horror could be inflicted on
another person, he likely tried it,
leaving him to believe he's just like
the parasites the police are hunting. He
also thinks it's the reason he can pick
them out in a crowd. Like recognizes
like and all that. On that note,
Shinichi might have a parasite in him,
but he's not crazy. So, Urugami tells
the police that Shinichi's normal.
Without a psychic or an ally to detect
parasites, the authorities have to get
creative about removing them. Hiramama
wants to use Urugami as their on-site
parasite detector, but the commander of
the armed forces, Yamagishi, disagrees.
At the same time, Hiokawa and Gooto have
their own meeting where they discuss
several of their parasite allies going
missing at once. They decide in that
moment that the government is to blame
and that they should do something about
it soon. Honestly, I'm surprised that
there's not a parasite in a higher
position than the mayor. While both
sides are preparing for war, Shinichi
returns to his everyday life, but that
lasts for about a day before Hiramama
shows up at his school to ask for his
help. Murano can't stand that her
boyfriend is constantly in harm's way
and crossing paths with the parasites.
But of course, Shinichi agrees to help.
He suggests that the government use
flamethrowers against the parasites
because the fire will startle them. But
they laugh it off. Yeah, sure. Ask this
guy for help and then don't take his
suggestion seriously. So, the
flamethrower idea is a bust. But the
next morning, the police raid the
building that Hiokawa turned into his
base. Uragami and Shinichi attend the
sweep to identify the parasites among
the evacuees, but they do so from an
armored vehicle outside. Unfortunately,
their powers don't work from a distance.
So, the police rely on an X-ray machine
that detects alien life forms. In the
20th episode, chaos unfolds. The
military locates a parasite through the
X-ray machine and makes quick work of
isolating and dispatching it. Then they
drag its body away to prepare for the
next one. As more evacuees leave without
any signs of parasites, the military
starts to worry that they've caught on
to their plan. They have all the people
from the building gathered in the lobby.
And that's where Mayor Hiokawa
approaches the military, saying there
are still civilians on the second floor
who won't come down if they see armed
people. He offers to get them, but
obviously he's just lying. General
Yamagishi tells his soldiers to stall
Hiokawa and potential parasites from
leaving so they can bring Uragami inside
where he can point them out. That's
where things get wild with the military
going a little stir crazy with their
guns. They try to shoot the parasites
but end up shooting the humans instead,
creating unnecessary casualties. At the
same time, some parasites act as a
distraction. During the chaos, Hiokawa
and his parasite allies sneak away to
the second floor, requiring assault
teams to go searching for them. Hiwa
decides there's no point in running, but
Goto is there and he wants to stick
around to study how his enemies fight.
He starts taking out the military squads
one by one. Since he has multiple
parasites in his body, he's pretty
intense and shows no mercy. It is a
blood bath wherever he goes. Even the
serial killer fears him as Uragami runs
away after meeting Goto's eyes, leaving
the squad he was with behind to die.
Meanwhile, the last remaining squad,
Yamagishi, catches up with Hiokawa. In
the 21st episode, Mayor Hiokawa greets
his audience without fear. He goes on a
rant about how humanity is a poison to
the earth, a poison that destroys
everything it comes into contact with,
throwing the delicate ecosystem out of
balance. In some ways, he's not wrong,
but that doesn't justify letting alien
parasites run rampant, now does it?
Anyways, the soldiers have the orders to
shoot on site. So, Hirokawa barely
finishes his speech before he's eating
bullets. Wait, we all thought he was a
parasite the entire time, right? Wrong.
The guy was a human who believed in the
parasites philosophy that much. Anyway,
Gooto catches up with the last squad and
promptly murders most of the soldiers
before following the rest toward the
roof. Yamagishi is the last one standing
and he goes down fighting, but he does
go down. Afterward, Goto goes down to
the street to have a word with Shinichi,
promising a one-on-one fight between the
two of them in the future. Taking on
dozens of soldiers tires him out, so he
postpones their fight. Oh, and that
Urugami guy escapes police custody and
goes on the lamb. This is a mess.
Anyway, Shinichi just goes back home
after that. He's pretty sure that Goto
is going to kill him. So, when Migi
falls asleep the next day, Shinichi
loses his mind. I'm talking outbursts,
hallucinations, attacking others. We're
20 episodes into this story, and I have
never seen him this scared. He
eventually settles down in a park he
likes where Murano tracks him down. He
can tell that something is wrong with
him and invites him to her place to
talk. Of course, her parents aren't
home, and they don't do much talking at
all. After spending the night with
Murano, though, Shinichi finds his
reason to keep fighting and decides he's
going to live no matter what it takes.
In the 22nd episode, Shinichi and Migi
face off against Goto one last time.
Migi senses Goto in their town, so
Shinichi goes on the run. Bro even
steals a car. We are pulling some Grand
Theft Auto in these final episodes,
gang. Migi takes the wheel and drives
towards some nearby mountains where they
can fight without civilian casualties.
He also has a plan.
>> Well,
>> it didn't work. Let's get out of here.
>> Where can we go?
>> Just run,
>> bro. survives that. Damn, fellas. I'm
all for rooting for the underdogs, but
this is not looking good. Once in the
woods, Shinichi and Migi realize they'll
need a flawless plan if they're going to
beat Goto. In their final fight, it's
going to come down to Brain versus
Braun. Migi separates himself from
Shinichi's arm, allowing them to attack
from two places at once. Unfortunately,
he can only stay detached for a few
minutes before his body gives out. So,
they spring their attack with Shinichi
distracting Gooto with fire while Migi
goes in to decapitate him.
Unfortunately, he doesn't get a clean
cut, which means Gooto can fight back.
Migi stays to fight, giving Shinichi the
chance to escape. With Migi gone,
Shinichi is totally alone and lost in
the woods. It's only a matter of time
before Gooto catches up with him and he
has nowhere to go. More importantly, he
only has one arm now and he's wounded.
He comes upon a house in the middle of
the night and the resident, a lonely
woman named Mitsuya, brings him in,
cleans him up, and gives him a place to
stay for a few days. She needs his
company as much as he needs hers, and
she manages to put some pep in his step
before he goes home. Unfortunately, on
the day he'll leave to go home, men from
Msio's village come to her door because
of a murder in the woods. They try to
blame Shinichi for the murder. But when
they go to look at the body, they
realize he couldn't be responsible.
Shinichi, knowing Gooto is now closing
in on the innocent village, goes out on
his own to finish what he started. His
lone weapon is a wood axe he takes from
Mitsuyo's place. In the 23rd episode,
Shinichi goes out to meet his maker. He
actually finds Goto in the woods, curled
up in a ball and asleep. In his
vulnerable state, Shinichi doesn't
hesitate to bring the wood cleaver down
on his neck. Unfortunately, Goto wakes
up in time to deflect the attack,
sending Shinichi on the defensive.
Hidden in the woods, Shinichi knows the
odds are stacked against him. Without
Migi, he doesn't stand a chance against
the strong parasite. That doesn't stop
him from trying, though. Shinichi is a
fighter, so he sharpens a stick and
climbs a tree, hoping to jab it through
a crack in Gooto's armor. Instead, he
gets caught midair and thrown into a
nearby tree. Things aren't looking good,
and he's definitely going to get himself
killed, but he has a rusty pipe and a
dream. He finds a pipe sticking out of
the ground, remembering a spot on
Gooto's side where he bled from a
gunshot wound and drives it in. His plan
actually works. He harms Goto, which
only makes him angrier. Goto goes to
land a killing blow, but Migi, revealed
to have been fused with Gooto's body,
and the other parasites inside it, stop
the attack. Then he detaches from Gooto
to reconnect with the residual parts of
him inside of Shinichi. Migi's back and
he's there to fight. When Migi leaves
Goto's body, the other parasites also
start pulling apart until his body
eventually bursts, further weakened by
Shinichi unknowingly poisoning him with
that rusty pipe. As they watch Goto
struggle to stay alive, our guys have a
moral debate. Migi can't bring himself
to murder one of his own kind anymore.
And Shinichi thinks that showing mercy
is a human trait to aspire to. But then
he thinks of his friends and family,
their safety, and kills Goto for good.
In the season finale, things start to
change for the better. After the
military wiped out all the parasites at
city hall, and our guys took down Goto
once and for all, the parasites slowly
faded into a distant memory. While some
believe their species went extinct,
others think they went into hiding,
choosing to conform to society to
survive. Either way, the mincemeat
murders ended and there was no one left
for Shinichi to hunt down. With peace
restored, Migi comes to Shinichi in a
dream one night, telling him that he
plans to go to sleep, only permanently
this time to fade into Shinichi's
consciousness so he can rest and take in
information in the same way he did when
morphed with Gooto. Migi encourages
Shinichi to forget him and carry on with
his life, but you know that little alien
is Shinichi's ride or die. A year passes
and Shinichi goes to meet with Murano
for a date. He looks good, guys. More
like his normal self from the start of
the series, but also changed, too. More
importantly, he's obviously happy and
he's working towards taking the entrance
exams to get into college since chasing
down parasites meant him missing out the
first time. Life is great, it seems,
until he's walking through the city and
notices Uraami tailing him. Seriously,
it's the finale. We couldn't have a
happy epilogue. Anyway, Uragami lures
them into a building and then takes
Murano hostage on the roof where he
calls Shinichi out for not being human.
Apparently, he knew the whole time that
he was a parasite, albeit different from
the others. He goes on a spiel about how
he's the definition of human nature and
wants to know what Shinichi makes of
him. Shinichi couldn't care less about
this guy. He wants his girl. So Uragami
throws Murano off the roof. Shinichi
runs for it, punching Uragami in the
face and trying to catch Murano, but he
isn't fast enough. He collapses to his
knees, grieving the loss of his first
and only love. When I tell you I stopped
breathing. There's like two minutes left
to the episode and this is what they do
with it. That's when Migi tells Shinichi
to snap out of it because he's tired and
he can't keep holding her forever.
Shinichi opens his eyes and there he is
leaning over the building while holding
Murano's hand. Thank god. He hauls her
to safety and they hold one another as
Shinichi stares off into the open blue
sky. And that's the entire story of
Parasite the Maxim. For a series about
invasive aliens, I didn't expect the
emotional whirlwind it put me through.
Hopefully Shinichi can make it into
college without another intergalactic
incident getting in the way. Are you
looking for another anime to fill the
migysized hole in your heart? Make sure
to check out some of my other videos
that you see right here. And in the
meantime, peace.